Bruno Gatiba Ngugi

Software Engineer

Personal Statement

From an early age, I was always fascinated by technology, this landed me into trouble a couple of times since I would end up tearing things apart to find out how various devices worked. One day I took apart my grandfather's radio, to try and figure out where the voices from the radio were coming from. Well, needless to say, the radio was never quite the same. With my immense passion for technology, I knew I would eventually end up dealing with computers. Several years later look at me now, a budding software engineer eager to get started on something that will take me on the path to achieving my goals.

Skills

Django	• • • • •	Angular	••••
Python	• • • • •	React	• • • • •
Javascript	• • • • •	Postgresql	••••
Git collaboration	• • • • •	Html	• • • • •
Css	• • • •		

Professional Experience

Sofware Engineer, *Noba technologies*

03/2021 - 07/2022

 Worked with a consortium of software developers to come up with smart pointof-sale systems for our clients. Kenya

- Managed to help clients increase sales and financial bookkeeping through the system.
- Helped manage customers' stock through tracking and insightful alerts on their current stock inventory.
- Skills Django, Django rest-framework, Postgresql, Angular js

Software developer consultant, self employed

02/2021 - present

- Provide expert knowledge to businesses on the best technological approach for their business.
- Set up online tools for businesses.
- Plan and review business websites and suggest revisions.
- Monitor software for updates and security.

Highlighted software applications

Farmer loaning application Web, role Front-end / Backend

07/2022 - 07/2022

- A web application where farmers apply for loans and get farm inputs as loans based on the crops that they plan to plant.
- The farm inputs (loan) provided are seeds, fertilizers pesticides, and herbicides.
- Technologies used:
- -Django for the back-end, Angular for the front-end, and Postgres for the database.

Highlited software applications

Awwards Website - independent project | Fullstack software engineer

06/2022 - 06/2022

- link ♂:
- A web application where users get to upload projects they have worked on.
- Users on the platform get to rate their work, using the following criteria design, usability, and content.
- Technologies used:
 - Django for the front-end and back-end.
 - Used Postgres for the database.

Pitch platform application, *Independent project* | *Fullstack software developer*

06/2022 - 06/2022

link -

- An application where users pitch their business ideas.
- Investors pleased by the idea contact the business owner and invest in the idea.
- Technologies used:
 - Figma to come up with the design of the project.
 - Django for both the front-end and back-end of the application.
 - Postgres for the database.

Git Search, independent project | Fullstack software developer

04/2022 - 04/2022

- A web application where users search for repositories based on the technologies used.
- Users can also search for repositories using GitHub profile names.
- Technologies used:
 - Angular for the whole application.
 - GitHub API.

Education

 Moringa school, certificate in software development Trained in web development basics (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, and Jquery) Advanced to front-end development using Angularjs. Later progressed to back-end development using Postgresql, Django, Flask 	
Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology, Diploma in Information Technology	09/2017 – 11/2021 Juja, Kenya
Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology CCNA2	2019 Juja , Kenya
Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriuculture and Technology CCNA 1	2019 Juja, Kenya
Koelel High school, KCSE	01/2013 – 12/2016 Nakuru, Kenya

Interests

Hobbies

Riding motorbikes, Badminton, Video games, and reading novels.

References

Available upon request